Privacy Policy
--------------

The Drug Policy Alliance (“**DPA,**”“**we,**” or “**us**”) understands the importance of protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy (“**Policy**”) describes what information we collect about you, including when and how we collect it, how we use it, with whom we may share it, and what choices you have regarding our use of your information. Your use of the website [www.drugpolicy.org](http://www.drugpolicy.org/) and all platforms, blogs, and features of the website (the “**Website**”) indicates your acceptance of this Policy. If you do not accept all of the terms of the Policy, you should not use the Website. This Policy may change, so please refer back to it periodically.

**How We Collect Information About You**.

* We may collect information about you when you use the Website. For example, we may collect information when you submit your email address, become a member of DPA, join our mailing list, make a donation, sign a petition, or communicate with us. You may generally browse the Website without providing any Personal Information (defined below)

**What Kinds of Information We Collect About You.**

We may collect two types of information from you:

* “Personal Information” is information that would allow someone to identify or contact you, including, for example, your name, address, phone number and email address. The personal information we collect might include your name, address, phone number, fax number, email address, and social media online identifiers. If you make a donation, become a member, or register for an event, you may be directed to a third-party website to process that transaction. They may collect additional information necessary to complete that transaction or application.
* “Non-identifiable Information” is information that does not reveal your specific identity, including browser and device information, access and usage data, Internet Protocol (IP) address, and Website usage information collected through cookies, pixel tags and other technologies – see further in “Cookies and Similar Tools” section below. Non-identifiable Information also includes information that has been anonymized or aggregated in a manner that no longer reveals your specific identity.

**How We Use Your Information**.

* DPA uses Personal Information collected about you to provide you with information, resources and services; enable you to participate in features on the Website; customize our content or communications to you based on your previous interactions with DPA, including donations; provide user support; communicate with you and respond to your inquiries; receive and track donations; register and manage participation in events and services; improve the content and features of the Website; and advance DPA’s mission.
* DPA uses Non-identifiable Information for internal purposes, for example, to manage and improve the Website, analyze usage patterns, customize and improve the user experience, and diagnose technical problem.
* We may combine Personal Information or Non-Identifiable Information we collect with information we obtain about you from third parties, and use such combined information in accordance with this Policy.
* In the event you make a donation or engage in other financial transactions, you grant us, and any payment processor we partner with, permission to access your credit card information or other financial information to complete your donation or financial transaction.

**When We Disclose Your Information.**

* DPA may share your Personal Information with its affiliated entities, agents, contractors, vendors, service providers and partners for the purposes of completing tasks, processing donations and providing services to you on our behalf. DPA will not share or sell Personal Information to unaffiliated mass marketers without your express permission.
* DPA may share or exchange Personal Information of current and former DPA members or donors with other nonprofit organizations whose missions align with DPA’s work.

Whenever you sign a petition on the Website, we may share your Personal Information with governmental bodies, public officials or outside organizations related to the petition.

* If law enforcement or judicial authorities require us to provide them with your Personal Information, we must cooperate with the authorities if their request is supported with the necessary legal documentation.
* If we or some or all of our assets are acquired by another organization, such as through a merger, acquisition, or bankruptcy, that organization will possess the information collected by us, and it will assume the rights and obligations regarding our information as described in this Policy.
* We may share Non-identifiable Information, including information that has been de-identified or aggregated and other technical information, without limitation.
* We reserve the right to disclose your Personal Information to protect the rights, property, safety or security of DPA, our users, or the public.

**Legal Basis for Processing**. Our legal basis for processing your Personal Information for the purposes described above will typically be consent, as you have consented to us using your Personal Information for the purposes discussed here. We may also process your Personal Information to enter into or perform a contract with you, or to comply with a legal obligation to which DPA is subject. It is also in our legitimate interest to use your Personal Information to operate and improve our services, measure our impact, and to protect our organization.

* DPA treats security seriously and takes reasonable measures to protect each Website user’s Personal Information. DPA is not, however, responsible for any information you share with other users of the Website or other third parties. While we strive to use industry-standard practices to protect your information, DPA cannot guarantee the absolute security of your information. If you believe there has been any breach of the security of the Website, please contact us.

**Your Control of Personal Information**.

* You may limit the collection and use of different elements of your Personal Information by not participating in those activities for which we collect Personal Information, as listed above. You may unsubscribe from communications you receive from us, or select the type of information you would like to receive, by following directions included in such communications, or by contacting us at the address below.
* You may discontinue the collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information by limiting or discontinuing your use of the Website altogether.
* You may request a copy of the Personal Information we hold about you by contacting us at the address below. You may ask us to correct any personal information or delete all information we hold about you by contacting us at the address below. We may be entitled, however, to decline the request or retain information under certain circumstances, under applicable laws.
* You may opt-out of our sharing of your Personal Information with other unaffiliated third party organizations by contacting us at the email address below and describing your request.

**Submitting Information to Public Areas of Website**. Please be aware that if you decide to disclose Personal Information on an area of the Website accessible to other users, this information may become public. DPA does not control the acts of users of the Website, so please be cautious when deciding to reveal Personal Information. Please contact us if you believe a user of the Website is improperly collecting or using information about you or other users.

**Cookies and Similar Tools**. We may use third-party analytics providers and technologies, including cookies, pixel tags, and similar tools, to assist in collecting information about your computer or device and your use of the Website. A cookie is a small piece of information that a website can store on a computer and later use to recognize a user. The purpose of cookies is to enhance your ability to receive the information you want. DPA may use cookies to enhance the experience of users of the Website. You may be able to personalize your browser settings to reject cookies, although certain features of the Website may not function as intended.

As we adopt additional technologies, we may also gather additional information through other methods.

**Privacy Protection for Children**. If you are under the age of 13, please do not use the Website. DPA will not knowingly permit persons under the age of 13 to provide information, make a donation, or sign up for updates or receive information, through the Website or otherwise. If DPA later learns that a user is under the age of 13, DPA will take appropriate steps to remove that user’s Personal Information from the database and restrict that user’s access to the Website.

**How Long We Hold Data.** We keep your Personal Information for as long as is necessary for the purposes for which it is processed. These periods vary depending on the nature of the information and your interactions with us.

**Links to Other Websites**. The Website may contain links to or frame third-party websites. DPA is not responsible for the privacy practices, policies, or content of those websites. Once you link to any third-party website, you are subject to the terms of service and privacy policy of that site. We encourage you to investigate and ask questions before disclosing information to third parties.

**Policy Revisions****.** DPA believes in respecting your privacy. We will update and amend this Policy if and when it is necessary. Please check back often to read our most updated and amended version, which is posted in the privacy policy section of the Website. Your continued use of the Website after revision means that you consent to our updates and amendments. If we amend this Policy materially with respect to Personal Information you have already supplied to us, we will take reasonable measures to notify you of the amended Policy, via email or other electronic medium, and provide you with the opportunity to opt-out of any new use of your Personal Information. Your failure to act after such notification will be considered as assent to the amended Policy.

**International Usage.** The Website is controlled, operated, and administered entirely within the United States. If you visit, access, interact with, and/or otherwise use the Website from a location outside the United States, please be advised that any information you provide in connection with any such activity may be processed in and/or transferred to the United States and/or other territories and locations, where privacy protections may not be as comprehensive as those in the territory or location where you interact with or otherwise use the Website. By using the Website, you affirmatively consent to the transfer, use, disclosure, provision, and other administration of your information as described in this Policy.

**Contact Information**. You may contact DPA about this Policy through any of the following ways:

* :**By Email****:** [\[email protected\]](https://drugpolicy.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

* **By Mail:**

Drug Policy Alliance

c/o Member Services

131 West 33rd Street, 15th Floor

New York, NY10001

* **By Phone:** 212-613-8025

**(Updated 10/20/2023)**
